Tracekeep is a local second brain for Codex, turning completed conversations into sourced memory and action.
Use Codex as usual.
This is the default daily entry point.
You do not need to say "remember this" or prefix a message with "Tracekeep."
When a meaningful turn completes, a trusted local hook classifies the result.
Durable conclusions become sourced Learning Notes; actions, decisions, and uncertain items become proposals the user can review.
Then ask inside Codex what unfinished work deserves attention today.
Tracekeep returns a short, focused list from the local store, with the original source and a concrete next action.
No browsing through folders or lists is required.
The user stays in the conversation instead of opening a dashboard just to remember what mattered.
Ask Tracekeep to resume one open loop, and it reconnects the earlier decision, what is still missing, and what to do next.
Codex can draft the next step while Tracekeep keeps the loop open.
When the reply arrives, tell Codex to update or close it, and the local history stays reversible.
Nothing is sent externally, and the source remains visible.
A local Stop hook calls tracekeepd through an authenticated loopback API.
Tracekeepd alone writes SQLite; sources, evidence, and FTS5 search stay local.
Capture begins after installation and never claims every historical chat.
Direct ChatGPT integration is planned, not shipped.
The Web Dashboard is only the supporting workspace for batch review, evidence, backup, and settings.
Here the user can inspect a proposed action, accept it, edit it, reject it, merge duplicates, or undo a change.
It is not the required daily entry point.
Tracekeep itself was built end to end in Codex with GPT-5.6.
From the product owner's problem and trust boundaries, Codex coordinated focused subagents
for requirements, interaction design, architecture, and implementation,
then regression tests, synthetic UAT, privacy review, Windows packaging, and documentation.
Codex also handled GitHub commits, pull requests, CI, release assets, captions, narration, and submission preparation.
Public PRs show automatic capture, the Windows release, and competition materials moving from decisions to a tested, downloadable product.